Guide to the Emilio Q. Daddario Congressional Papers, 1959 - 1970
Emilio Q. Daddario Congressional Papers, 1959 - 1970
- Series 7: Science and Aeronautics Policy, 1959-1970
  - Space
    - Bioastronautics
      - Space Medicine
      - Bioastronautics reports and proceedings, 1962
      - USAF Bioastronautics/NASA Space Medicine, August 1963
      - Lectures in Aerospace Medicine, February 3-7, 1964
      - Bioastronautics Data Book, 1964
      - Life Sciences Trip, January 13, 1966
    - Manned Space Flight
      - Supply Support Systems, 1961 (Box 39)
        Oversize: see box 42.
      - Lunar Orbit Rendezvous, News Conference, July 11, 1962
      - Spacecraft Environmental Control System: Capability and Status, 1962
      - Subcommittee meeting transcript, March 29, 1963
      - Presentation of the Kennedy Space Center, January 27, 1964
      - NASA Presentation to the Committee at Houston, February 15, 1964
      - Draft of Hearing at Huntsville, Alabama, January 24, 1964
      - Photographs of Gemini III, 1965
      - Grumman Trip, March 12, 1965
      - Photos of Grumman Trip, March 12, 1965
      - Crawler-Transporter, 1965
      - Fact sheets, memoranda, pamphlets, 1965
      - Correspondence, reports, 1966
      - Hearing questions and statements, 1966
        No folder.
      - Manned Space Flight Committee Report, 1967
      - Apollo Accident, January 27, 1967
      - Photographs with astronauts, correspondence, 1967, 1969
      - Apollo Spacecraft (remarks)
    - Missiles
      - Commercial Application of Missile/Space Technology, September 1963
      - Missiles and Rockets article on EQD, August 10, 1964
      - Stage O for Saturn-IB, November 1964
      - Miami-Dade Resolution, 1965
      - General Information: Down Range Stations, Atlantic Missile Range
    - Moon
      - Articles, drafts, pamphlets, speeches, 1963-1966
      - Ranger VIII Moon photographs, 1965
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA)
      - Reports and articles for the committee on Science and Astronautics, 1961-1966
      - NASA Procurement pamphlet, 1962-1965
      - Webb Luncheon, October 1, 1962
      - NASA International Programs, 1962
        Oversize: see Box 42.
      - House Remarks, NASA Authorization Bill, drafts included, 1963
      - The Space Program and the Future, speech by Addison M. Rothrock, June 8, 1963
      - NASA Subcontracts Guide, 1963
      - NASA Electronics Center, 1963-1964
      - Statements before S&A Committee, memoranda, 1964
      - NASA Research and Development budget, 1964
      - NASA Briefing for the President, August 1, 1964
      - Articles, correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, 1965
      - NASA Budget recommendation, 1966 (Box 40)
      - Memoranda, press releases, speeches, 1966
      - S&A Committee Hearing Testimony, March 11, 1966
      - NASA Authorization, 1968
      - NASA Budget Amendment, 1970
    - Russian Space Program
      - Congressman Teague's Proposed Resolution on US/USSR Space Cooperation, 1963
      - Speech Material, Russian Space Program, 1966
    - Satellites
      - Navigation Satellite System, January 30, 1964
    - Miscellaneous
      - Articles, speeches, 1965
      - Space Business Daily, February 13, 1969 and May 8, 1969
  - Technology
    - Scientific and Technical Personnel in Industry, 1960
    - Articles by C.S. Draper of MIT, 1962-1964
    - Technology Assessment, 1962-1970
    - Harvard Program on Technology and Society, 1965-1968
    - Harvard Program on Technology and Society, May 22, 1965
    - State Technical Services Bill, 1965
      Two copies.
    - Articles, reports, 1965
    - Michael Michaelis articles and correspondence, 1965
    - Science Panel, January 25-27, 1966
    - President's Commission on Law Enforcement, 1966
    - Harvard Program on Technology and Society, October 20-21, 1966
    - Carnegie Institute of Technology, 10 Years of Progress, 1957-1967
    - Technology Assessment Seminar, Proceedings before the House subcommittee on Science, Research, and Development, September 21-22, 1967
    - Technology Assessment, 1968
    - Panel on Science and Technology, January 23-25, 1968
    - Harvard Program on Technology and Society, May 1969
    - Panel, 1969
    - Engineering Manpower Commission report, 1969
    - Harvard Program on Technology and Society, November 1969
    - Technology Assessment, 1969-1970
    - Technology Assessment Clippings, 1969-1970
    - Taming Technology from Future Shock, by Alvin Toffler, 1970
    - Panel meeting, 1970
    - Harvard Program on Technology and Society, 1970
  - Miscellany
    - Articles, papers, and statements on Science, Soviet Space progress, Law enforcement, Wesleyan University, and the Peace Corps, 1951-1969 (Box 41)
    - Various papers on Government Research
    - Press Releases and Speeches, 1958-1968
    - Newspaper clippings, 1959-1969
    - Daddario's Congressional Voting Record, 1959-1970
      Oversize: see box 42. Six books.
    - Indian Agricultural Research Institute pamphlets, 1963-1965
    - Dr. Milton J. Freiwald papers on eye infections, 1965
    - Articles, correspondence, reports, 1965
    - National Science Foundation report on Science Education in the Schools of the United States, 1965
    - Newspaper clippings, 1966
    - Science Information Steering Committee, August 16, 1967
    - Connecticut Academy of Sciences (proposed), 1968
    - Council of Communications (William T. Knox), 1968
    - Science clippings, 1968-1969
    - Articles, clippings, correspondence, 1968-1969
    - Articles, correspondence, 1968-1969
    - Articles, 1969
    - Articles, correspondence, 1969-1970
    - Standard Reference Data, 1970
    - Magazines
      First set indexed. Second set includes Air Force and Space Digest, Astronautics and Aeronautics, CSIR News, three CSIR pamphlets, Journal and Register, Journal of Scientific and Industrial Research, Science and Technology, and Strategic Industries Bulletin.
  - Oversize (Box 42)
    - National Science Foundation
      - Index to Legislative History of NSF, 1945-1950
        From Box 33.
    - Patents
      - Bills, correspondence, reports, 1965
        From Box 35.
    - Space
      - Manned Space Flight
        - Supply Support Systems, 1961
          From Box 39.
        - NASA Presentation to the Committee at Houston, February 15, 1964
      - National Aeronautics and Space Administration
        - NASA International Programs, 1962
        - House remarks, NASA Authorization Bill, drafts included, 1963
    - Miscellany
      - Press Releases and Speeches, 1958-1968
        From Box 41.
      - Daddario's Congressional Voting Record, 1959-1970
        From Box 41. Six books.
      - Dr. Milton J. Freiwald papers on eye infections, 1965
- Series 8: Interparliamentary Union
  - American Assembly, 1962 (Box 43)
  - American Assembly, Outer Space Discussion
  - American Assembly, U.S. and Canada, 1964
  - Asian-American Assembly photos, 1963
  - Asian-American Assembly reports, 1963-1964
  - Asian-American Assembly general correspondence, 1963
  - Asian-American Assembly articles, 1963
  - Asia: Papers on cultural background, 1963
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1963
  - Interparliamentary Union Meetings
    - Belgrade, 1963
    - Lausanne, Switzerland, 1963
    - Lucerne - Geneva, 1964 (Box 44)
    - Copenhagen, 1964
    - Tehran, Iran
  - Study on the United Nations, 1964
  - Study on the United Nations, 1966
- Series 9: Wesleyan University
  - 1963 (Box 45)
  - Departmental, Committee Reports, 1962-1963
  - Correspondence
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1964
  - Proposed dormitories
  - Budgets, faculty appointments, minutes of board meetings, departmental reports, 1963-1964
- Series 10: Miscellany
  - Appropriations Committee, 1968 (Box 46)
  - Armed Services Committee, 1959-1961
  - Department of Commerce
  - Department of Defense
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1966
    - Air Force, 1961
    - Army, 1969
    - Navy, 1963
  - Defense Contract Awards, 1966, 1967, 1970
  - Federal Communications Commission, 1962 order
  - Government Operations Committee, 1958-1959
  - Health, Education and Welfare, National Institute of Health, 1967
  - Department of the Interior, 1967
  - Judiciary Committee, 1958-1961
  - Justice Department, 1961: R. Kennedy letter
  - Post Office Department, 1960
  - Rules Committee, 1961-1962
  - Small Business Committee, 1965-1967
  - State Department, 1967
  - Un-American Activities Committee, Leg. 1961
  - Ways and Means, 1958, 1961
  - Invitations accepted and declined, 1962-1970 (Box 47)
    Filed chronologically by month.
  - Miscellaneous requests, March 1967-April 1969 (Box 48)
    Many months are missing.
  - Miscellaneous requests, September 1969-November 1970 (Box 49)
  - Brookings Institute, 1963-1967 (Box 50)
  - Congressional Record Inserts, 1959, 1963, 1964, 1968, 1969
  - Congressional Record Subscriptions, 1968-1970
  - Ditchley Foundation, Balance of Payments Conference, January 28, 1966
  - Personal congratulations, letters of praise, testimonial dinner, thank you letters, sympathy letters
    Includes two letters from Lyndon Johnson.
  - Recommendations, 1968-1970 (Box 51)
  - Speaker requests, 1969-1970
  - Appointment requests, 1968-1969
  - Television - radio scripts, 1963-1964
  - Travel
    Includes European trip, 1962, and Vietnam trip, 1965.
  - Sports Illustrated Silver Anniversary Award, 1963
  - Kennedy State of the Union Message, 1961
  - Federal appointments, 1967-1970 (Box 52)
  - Report of Congressional visitors to the U.S. Coast Guard Academy, 1962
  - Flag requests, 1968-1970
  - Articles, Testimony, Guests, Appointments, Etc.
    - Magazines with Daddario as article author or mention (Box 53)
      Science News, February 21, July 25, and November 7, 1970; Science, June 24, 1966, December 13, 1968, and November 6, 1970; and Scientific American, January 1970.
    - NASA Atlas-Centaur Launch Vehicle report to Committee on Science and Astronautics, March 1963
    - National Academy of Sciences report to Committee on Science and Astronautics on Basic Research and Goals, March 1965
    - Annual Report of Harvard's Program on Technology and Society, 1969-1970
    - Preserving the Future of Long Island Sound, Hearings before Subcommittee on Executive reorganization and Government Research, July 7, 8, 20, 1970
      Three booklets.
    - Guest books, 1959-1961, 1961-1962, 1963-1965, 1965-1967, 1968-1970
      Five books.
    - Appointment books, 1960-1970
      Nine books, for all years except 1967 and 1968.
    - Photos at U.S. Coast Guard Academy, undated